Guide to the Delta Chi Fraternity (Cornell University) records, 1899-2012.
Delta Chi Fraternity (Cornell University) records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Delta Chi Fraternity (Cornell University) records, 1899-2012.
37-4-734
Delta Chi Fraternity (Cornell University)
6.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Memorabilia, Manuscripts, Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications, Scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes and membership lists, and other chapter history.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes and membership lists, 1899-1988; completed chapter and house meeting report forms (typescript carbon copies, 1951-1964); personnel records, 1957-1964; purchasing records, 1956-1957; rushing books, bylaws, and other pamphlets; scrapbook by William Duke, Jr., 1905; group photographs of fraternity members and Fall, Spring, and Interfraternity Council Weekend events; photograph albums, 1970-1973; "The Chronology of Delta Chi"; abstract of title for 102 The Knoll; materials relating to the sale of the house; and blueprints. Also newsletter, "Cornell Delt," various years 1965-2009 and brochure, "Delta Chi: The Knoll," ca. 1968; Honor Roll of Donors, 1984-85, 1997-98.
Law books from the original Delta Chi library include Miscellaneous Reports New-York, no. 41 Scherer 20, June to November 1903; Miscellaneous Reports New-York, Lester 6 February to April 1907; Miscellaneous Reports New-York, no. 62 (missing title page); A Selection of Cases on the Law of Suretyship, James Barr Ames, Cambridge, 1901; and Cases on the Law of Sales of Goods, Frederick Campbell Woodward, American Case Book Series, St. Paul, West Publishing Co., 1913. Some are signed by students.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Delta Chi Fraternity (Cornell University); Duke, William,; Cornell University--Students.
Subjects:
Greek letter societies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
This guide provides only a partial descripton of what is contained within the collection.
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to members of Delta Chi Fraternity or by permission of the fraternity.
CONTAINER LIST
- Chapter Meeting Reports Sept 25, 1951 through Sept 15, 1954. Book – “Docket” on the spine – Cornell Chapter Delta Chi Record – Fall Term 1899 through May 31, 1914 meeting notes. Includes a description of the house fire Jan 28, 1900, 1 fatality, building a total loss. Spring term 1900 chapter moves into 123 Quarry St. facilities. Larger Book labeled “Docket” also – Meeting notes Sept 24, 1914 through April 14, 1941 (Box 1)
- Bylaws Dec 7, 1947. Personnel Records 1952-1964. Chapter Meeting Reports Dec 6, 1954 through Dec 7, 1964 (Box 2)
- Rush Books (1961) and (1966?). Booklet: The Proposal to make a gift of the Delta Chi house at Ithaca, New York, to Cornell University as a Residence Hall in conjunction with the College of Law. Booklet: Delta Chi since 1890. Bylaws: 1947, 1957, 1960, 1962, 1964, 1966. House Rules: 1966. Expulsion papers for Carl Alphonse Jaeger Oct 18, 1942, summons to expel Keith Richard Dowling (4-8-72). “C”’s notebook 1968. Cornell Delta Chi Executive Board Minutes Feb 4, 1969 - Oct 20, 1975. Delta Chi Quarterlies Sept ‘46 - May ‘47. Publications: Hear Ye - The Cornell Chapter of Delta Chi Plans to Build a new House, good pictures of the Knoll before construction. Hear Ye - The Cornell Chapter of Delta Chi has built a new House, good pictures of the new house. Personnel Records Class of ’68 and ’69 also ’33, ’36, ’44, ’49, ‘52. Meeting Reports: January 13, 1925 - Sept 16, 1951. January 1965 - May 13, 1968, March 3, 1969 - Nov 10, 1975. Honor Roll of Donors, 1984-85, 1997-98; Rush Book, 2007; and Homecoming Weekend flyer, 2011 (Box 3)
- Chapter Financial Records March ’68 – Dec ‘68, September ’71 - Jan ‘72, July ’72 - Sept ‘75. (Box 4)
- Guest Book – Rush 1968 - 1974 - Listing of who came to smokers. 11th Annual Report of the Interstate Commerce Commission – Property of the Library of the Delta Chi Fraternity. Delta Chi Cornerstone 1985. Quarterly Nov ’69, Feb ’70, May ’70, Summer ’87, Winter ’85-’86, Spring ‘87. Book: House Meeting Notes Dec 1, 1981 through Nov 16, 1980. Book: House Meeting Notes Sept 3, 1981through April 19, 1988. Photo: Delta Chi House Party May 1919. Good photos of current house, in early days. Two Books of Quarterlies 9-’37 through 5 – ‘43. Several copies of “The Delt”. Composite Photos ’61, ’63, ’66, ’67, ’68, ’72, ’76, ’88, ‘89. Purchasing Book, March, 1956 through 1957. Rush Book ‘63 Photos: Junior Weekend 1926, Fall Weekend ‘70, Mandolin Club 1926 and 1929, Spring Weekend ‘72, IFC Weekend ’60 Homecoming ‘73, Spring Weekend ’61 Toga Party, IFC Weekend ‘73, Fall Weekend ’61, Spring Weekend ‘73, Spring Weekend ’62, Homecoming ‘74, Spring Weekend ’63, IFC Weekend ‘74, Fall Weekend ’63, Spring Weekend ‘74, Spring Weekend ’64, Homecoming ‘75, Fall Weekend ’64, Fall Weekend ‘75, IFC Weekend ‘75, Spring Weekend ‘75. (Box 5)
- Misc Photographs: A few ‘60s era, Several appear to be 1900s. Post Cards sent to James T. O’Conner at Delta Chi 1920s. Large Bound Volume: Chapter Meeting Reports Sept 11, 1968 through April 1986. Personnel Records – Date of Initiation Jan 27, 1969 – 1988. Large Scrap Book – Started 1902 by William Duke Jr.. Article on Delta Chi purchase of old Alpha Delta Phi House (only two other chapters have purchased houses i.e. Michigan and New York University). Photos of Cornell Delegates to the 12th annual convention in New York City. Nice Large Photo of interior of the first Delta Chi house. Photos of Hugh P. Henry, Harold ?, Dean L. Kelsey, P.J. Richardson, H. P. Henry ’05, Tom S. Peace - captain, Andrew Rutledge Jr., Harold Prexy ’05 of the Cornell cricke team 1903-1905, J.T. Driscoll, A.R. Cornwall, George J. Nelbach. Photos of Cornell Spring Day 1904. Large Photo of Georgetown Delta Chi members 1904. Leather bound “The Tenth Annual Convention Banquet of Delta Chi Fraternity”. Much information on Cornell, Cornell athletics, and Delta Chi – not all photos identified. (Box 6)
- Notebook - Delta Chi Title – compiled by Roy Payne – many documents related to the title of the Delta Chi House on the Knoll. In which the New York Dept of State states “Cornell Chapter of Delta Chi”, a membership corporation filed April 19, 1900 in Ithaca, NY. “Sir Edward Coke Foundation” a membership corp. filed Aug 14, 1950, Ithaca. Newspaper article on Judge Edward Richard O’Malley. Misc. Papers: Treasurer’s Report Oct 16, 1965. Information similar to and in addition to the notebook listed above concerning the title to the house. Letter from John Trussel ’28 to Kirk Fry ’83 which is a History of Delta Chi and our chapter at Cornell. Scrap Book – Photo Album – Photos from ’72 & ‘73. Composites and other photos 1960s-200s (Box 7)
- Delta Chi Quarterly - July 1912 - sketch & photo reproduction of new house on the Knoll. Booklet: The Proposal to make a gift of the Delta Chi House at Ithaca, New York to Cornell University as a residence hall in conjunction with the College of Law. Some nice photos in this booklet. Certificate of Incorporation - Chapter Control Board Documents relating to Delta Chi House renovation and title. Letters Relating to the Title 1962-1963. Certificate of Incorporation – Sir Edward Coke Foundation, 1950. Documents related to the Sir Edward Coke Foundation. Documents related to Division of Historic Preservation in Ithaca 1987. Library dedication ceremony (2010), Reviving The Knoll (2007), The Foundation Chronicle Annual Report (2007), Delta Chi Quarterly (2012), copy of composite photograph (2005), House Improvement Report (1961), Funding The Knoll. (Box 8)
- Scans of some material including composites and photos 1960s-2000s, The Cornell Delta and Delta Chi quarterly publications; contains DVD-678 (Box 8)
- Minutes, 1941-1959 (Box 9)
- [REMOVED] Construction documents and related financial papers, 2005-2008 (Box 10 [REMOVED])
- Cornell Correspondence, 1897-1919 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1920-1921 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1923-1929 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1930-1932 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1940-1949 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1950-1959 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Cornell Correspondence, 1977-2011 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Law books from the original Delta Chi library (some are signed by students) - Miscellaneous Reports New-York, no. 41 Scherer 20, June to November 1903; Miscellaneous Reports New-York, Lester 6 February to April 1907; Miscellaneous Reports New-York, no. 62 (missing title page); A Selection of Cases on the Law of Suretyship, James Barr Ames, Cambridge, 1901; and Cases on the Law of Sales of Goods, Frederick Campbell Woodward, American Case Book Series, St. Paul, West Publishing Co., 1913., 1901-1913 (Box 12)
- Renovation plans (Map-case Folder 1)
- Renovation plans (Map-case Folder 2)